Inventory of the Paul B. Henze papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Central Asia File, 1948-2000 (Box 163-170)
  - Conference files, 1978-2000
    - "Impact of Islamic Nationalism on Soviet Domestic and Foreign Policy," Office of Soviet Analysis, Central Intelligence Agency, 1990 October (Box-folder 165: 2-3)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies, Phoenix, Arizona, 1992 November 19-22 (Box-folder 165: 4)
    - "Deepening U.S. Engagement with the States of Central Asia and the Caucasus: A Roadmap for the Future," Central Asia Institute, 1997 July 21 (Box-folder 165: 5)
    - Seminar on Kazakhstan, U.S. Department of State, Washington, D.C., 1998 September 22 (Box-folder 165: 6)
    - "Central Asia and the South Caucasus: Re-Orientations, Internal Transitions, and Strategic Dynamics," National Intelligence Council, Airlie House, Warrenton, Virginia, 2000 April 5-7 (Box-folder 165: 7)
  - Travel files, 1988-1998
    - "Heart of Asia" tour, led by Henze for the Smithsonian, 1988 September-October (Box-folder 165: 8-13, Box-folder 166: 1-5)
      Includes correspondence among participants, printed matter, photographs, and a trip report.
    - "American Turkish Friendship Council Trade and Investment Mission to Central Asia,", 1992 May-June (Box-folder 166: 6)
    - Central Asia tour, 1996 August (Box-folder 166: 7-8)
    - North Atlantic Council tour of Central Asia, 1998 June-July (Box-folder 166: 9-11)
  - Research materials, 1959-2000
    Includes clippings and collected articles.
    - General clippings, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 167: 1-5)
    - Afghanistan, 1976-1990 (Box-folder 167: 6)
    - Basmachi movement, 1987 (Box-folder 167: 7)
    - Drug trafficking, 2000 (Box-folder 167: 8)
    - Economics, 1994 (Box-folder 167: 9)
    - Islam, 1959-1998 (Box-folder 167: 10)
    - Kazakhstan, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 167: 11-12)
    - Kyrgyzstan, 1985-1998 (Box-folder 167: 13)
    - Maps, 1980s-2000s (Box-folder 167: 14-16)
    - Mongolia, 1990 (Box-folder 168: 1)
    - Relations with Russia, 1994 (Box-folder 168: 2)
    - Sufism, 1978 (Box-folder 168: 3)
    - Tajikistan, 1978-1999 (Box-folder 168: 4)
    - Textiles, 1982 (Box-folder 168: 5)
    - Turkestan, 1959, 1992 (Box-folder 168: 6-7)
    - Turkmenistan, 1993 (Box-folder 168: 8)
    - Tuva, 1992 (Box-folder 168: 9)
    - Uighurs, 1996, undated (Box-folder 168: 10)
    - Uzbekistan, 1996-1999, undated (Box-folder 168: 11)
    - Xinjiang, 1975-1994, undated (Box-folder 168: 12)
  - Printed matter, 1950s-2000
    Includes newspapers in Uzbek.
    - AACAR Bulletin (Association for the Advancement of Central Asian Research), 1993 (Box-folder 169: 1)
    - Aalam, 1992 (Box-folder 169: 2)
    - Center for Strategic and International Studies, 1994 (Box-folder 169: 3)
    - Central Asia-Caucasus Analyst, 2000 (Box-folder 169: 4)
    - Central Asia Report, 1990 (Box-folder 169: 5)
    - Cyber-Caravan, 1999 (Box-folder 169: 6)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 169: 7)
    - "ERK" demokratik partiiasi gazeta, 1992 (Box-folder 169: 8-9)
    - Inner Asia Report, 1990 (Box-folder 169: 10)
    - Iron Curtain over Eastern Turkistan, by Isa Yusuf Alptakin, 1950s (Box-folder 169: 11)
    - Islam nuri, 1993 (Box-folder 169: 12)
    - Khalq sŭzi, 1992 (Box-folder 169: 13)
    - Kishlok khakikati, 1992 (Box-folder 170: 1)
    - Kyrgyzstan Chronicle, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 170: 2-3)
    - Moskovskie novosti: regional'nyi vypusk dlia Kyrgyzstana i Kazakhstana, 1994 (Box-folder 170: 4)
    - Narodnoe slovo: gazeta Verkhovnogo soveta Respubliki Uzbekistan, 1992 (Box-folder 170: 5)
    - Ozgon nuru, 1994 (Box-folder 170: 6)
    - Pravda vostoka, 1992 (Box-folder 170: 7)
    - Slovo Kyrgyzstana, 1994 (Box-folder 170: 8)
    - Turkistan News and Information Network, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 170: 9)
    - Turkistan Newsletter, 1997 (Box-folder 170: 10)
    - Turkistan Today, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 170: 11)
    - Uzbekiston ovozi, 1992 (Box-folder 170: 12)
    - Vechernii Bishkek, 1994 (Box-folder 170: 13)
    - Voice of Turkistan, 1956 (Box-folder 170: 14)
- Miscellany, 1967-1995 (Box 171-176)
  Divided into two subseries: travel and research materials. The travel file contains correspondence, notes, printed matter, and photographs. Research materials contains clippings, collected articles, and other printed matter.
  - Travel files, 1967-1990
    - Mexico, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 171: 1-5)
    - Israel, 1971 November (Box-folder 171: 6-8)
    - India (Kashmir, Ladakh and Zanskar), 1986 September (Box-folder 171: 9-13, Box-folder 172: 1-4)
      Includes photographs of villages in Kashmir.
    - Himalayas, 1988 July 22-August 11 (Box-folder 172: 5)
    - Bhutan, 1988 September (Box-folder 172: 6)
    - Yemen, 1989 (Box-folder 172: 7-8)
    - Pakistan, China, Turkey and Poland, 1990 August 29-October 2 (Box-folder 172: 9)
  - Research materials, 1967-1995
    - By subject, 1971-1995
      - General, 1979-1995 (Box-folder 173: 1-5)
      - China, 1978-1995 (Box-folder 173: 6)
      - Clinton, Bill, 1994 (Box-folder 173: 7)
      - Giray family tree, 1982 (Box-folder 173: 8)
      - Lebanon, 1986 (Box-folder 173: 9)
      - RAND corporation, 1988 (Box-folder 174: 1)
      - Russia, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 174: 2-4)
      - Soviet Union, 1971-1983
        - Army, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 174: 5)
        - Corruption, 1983 (Box-folder 174: 6)
        - Nationalism, 1971-1981 (Box-folder 174: 7)
      - Tatarstan, 1992 (Box-folder 174: 8)
    - By title, 1967-1995
      Includes newspapers and magazines from Poland and Russia.
      - Argun, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 175: 1)
      - Bankovskaia gazeta, 1991 (Box-folder 175: 2)
      - Detektyw, 1991 (Box-folder 175: 3)
      - Gazeta Samorządowa, 1991 (Box-folder 175: 4)
      - Institute of Current World Affairs newsletters, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 175: 5-7)
      - Kobieta i Mężczyzna, 1991 (Box-folder 176: 1)
      - Na Przełaj, 1991 (Box-folder 176: 2)
      - Ramparts, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 176: 3)
      - St. Petersburg Times, 1995 (Box-folder 176: 4)
      - Times Literary Supplement, 1983 (Box-folder 176: 5)
      - Zarządzanie, 1991 (Box-folder 176: 6)
      - Zbójnicki: Pismo Satyryczne, 1990 (Box-folder 176: 7)
- Incremental materials not yet described (Box 177-189)
- 2014 April Incremental Materials, 1944-2010 (Box 190-216)
  - Chronological file, 1969-2010 (Box 190-191)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes correspondence, transcribed diary entries, writings, articles, and printed matter, all arranged chronologically.
    - 1969-1996 (Box-folder 190: 1-19)
    - 1997-2010 (Box-folder 191: 1-14)
  - Transcribed diaries, 1968-1984, 1998 (Box 191-192)
    - Ethiopian travels, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 191: 15-18)
    - Down the Awash, 1970 (Box-folder 191: 19)
    - Gurage country, 1970 (Box-folder 191: 20)
    - Ankober - Mitaw - Aliyu Amba, 1970 (Box-folder 191: 21)
    - Rift Valley Lakes, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 191: 22)
    - Southern religious sites, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 191: 23)
    - Addis Ababa, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 191: 24)
    - Jiru - Manz, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 191: 25)
    - Through Asia, 1998 (Box-folder 191: 26)
    - Journeys in Shoa - notes, outlines, etc., 1970-1984 (Box-folder 192: 1)
    - Travels in Israel, Kenya, Ethiopia, Germany, France, England, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 192: 2)
  - Ernest Benn, Ltd., 1973-1989 (Box-folder 192: 3-5)
  - "Layers of Time,", 2000s
  - Staff meeting notes, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 192: 7)
    Scope and Contents Note
    Notes written in Gregg shorthand.
  - "Three Decades of Arms for the Horn of Africa" by Paul B Henze, 1990 (Box-folder 192: 8)
  - Correspondence file II, 1958-2009 (Box 193-201)
    - General correspondence, 2008 (Box-folder 193: 1)
    - Rita and Richard Pankhurst, 2008 (Box-folder 193: 2)
      Includes transcribed diary entries as well as correspondence.
    - Correspondence, 2008-2009 (Box-folder 193: 3-7)
    - Mehmet Saray, 1987-2001 (Box-folder 194: 1)
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1958-1965 (Box-folder 194: 2)
      Includes correspondence, printed matter, and newsletters.
    - Shorthand notes, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 194: 3)
    - Radio Free Europe, 1952-2005 (Box-folder 194: 4)
      Includes German newspaper clippings, as well as memoranda.
    - RFE/RL correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 194: 5)
    - Correspondence, 2009 (Box-folder 194: 6)
    - Ethiopian Embassy WDC, 1999-2007 (Box-folder 194: 7)
    - Gerd Graber, 2004 (Box-folder 194: 8)
    - Russia's encounter with Islam, 2010 (Box-folder 194: 9)
    - General correspondence, 1999-1995 (Box-folder 194: 10-11, Box-folder 195: 1-8, Box-folder 196: 1-2)
    - Letters to be filed, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 196: 3)
    - Extra copies of family correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 196: 4)
    - Correspondence from Grace Heck to Gwyneth Hill, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 196: 5)
    - General correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 196: 6-13)
    - General correspondence, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 197: 1-9)
    - General correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 198: 1-9)
    - General correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 199: 1-8)
    - Negatives, 1980-1990s (Box-folder 199: 9)
    - CD-Rs (Box-folder 199: 10)
      Scope and contents note
      Contains 4 CD-Rs.
    - 1 VHS tape titled "Zero Hour: the Plot to Kill the Pope,", 2005 (Box 200: 1)
    - General correspondence, 2001-2008 (Box-folder 200: 2-8)
    - Heart attack correspondence, 2008 (Box-folder 200: 9)
    - Christmas letter, 2009 (Box-folder 200: 10)
    - Correspondence with Stan Chojnacki, 1973-1999 (Box-folder 201: 1-8)
    - Vladimir Socor Columns, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 201: 9)
    - Nancy Mitchell, 2007 (Box-folder 201: 10)
  - Travel materials, 1990-2006 (Box 201-202)
    Includes correspondence, printed materials, travel documentation, and notes.
    - Trip to Egypt and Israel, 1990 May 24-1990 June 10 (Box-folder 201 :1)
    - Alaska, 2006 (Box-folder 201: 12)
    - Europe, 2002 April-May (Box-folder 201: 13)
    - Turkey, 2004 (Box-folder 201: 14)
    - Slovenia, 1999 (Box-folder 201: 15, Box-folder 202: 1)
    - World Affairs Council and Cincinnati Art Museum, 2006 (Box-folder 202: 2)
    - Georgian Foundation for Strategic and International Studies conference, 2007 (Box-folder 202: 3)
    - Orbis Aethiopicus, 2007 (Box-folder 202: 4)
  - Georgia crisis, 2007 (Box-folder 202: 5)
  - Personal files (Box-folder 202: 6-7)
  - Diaries, notes, and journals in Gregg shorthand, 1950-2002 (Box 202-211)
    Contains bound diaries, unbound notes, and daily logs, all in Gregg shorthand.
    - Diary, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 202: 8)
    - Diary, 1955-1968 (Box-folder 203: 1)
    - Diary, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 203: 2)
    - 1977 January-February (Box-folder 203: 3)
    - 1977 February-April (Box-folder 203: 4)
    - 1977 April-June (Box-folder 203: 5)
    - 1977 May-June (Box-folder 203: 6)
    - 1977 June-October (Box-folder 203: 7)
    - 1977 July-August (Box-folder 204: 1)
    - 1977 August-December (Box-folder 204: 2)
    - Bound diary, 1978 January-June (Box-folder 204: 3)
    - 1978 January-February (Box-folder 204: 4)
    - 1978 March-April (Box-folder 204: 5)
    - 1978 May (Box-folder 204: 6)
    - 1978 June (Box-folder 204: 7)
    - 1978 July-August (Box-folder 204: 8)
    - 1978 July-October (Box-folder 204: 9)
    - 1978 July-December (Box-folder 204: 10)
    - 1978 September (Box-folder 204: 11)
    - 1978 October (Box-folder 205: 1)
    - 1978 November (Box-folder 205: 2)
    - 1978 November-1979 February (Box-folder 205: 3)
    - 1978 December (Box-folder 205: 4)
    - Bound diary, 1978 May-1979 January (Box-folder 205: 5)
    - 1979 January (Box-folder 205: 6)
    - 1979 January-February (Box-folder 205: 7)
    - Bound diary, 1979 February-July (Box-folder 205: 8)
    - 1979 March (Box-folder 206: 1)
    - 1979 April (Box-folder 206: 2)
    - 1979 April-July (Box-folder 206: 3)
    - 1979 May (Box-folder 206: 4)
    - 1979 June (Box-folder 206: 5)
    - 1979 July (Box-folder 206: 6)
    - 1979 July-August (Box-folder 206: 7)
    - 1979 July-October (Box-folder 206: 8)
    - 1979 August (Box-folder 206: 9)
    - 1979 August-November (Box-folder 206: 10)
    - European American Workshop visit to Turkey, 1979 September 8-16 (Box-folder 206: 11)
    - 1979 September (Box-folder 207: 1)
    - 1979 October (Box-folder 207: 2)
    - 1979 November (Box-folder 207: 3)
    - 1979 November-December (Box-folder 207: 4)
      Notebook written in Gregg shorthand.
    - 1979 December (Box-folder 207: 5)
    - 1979 December-1980 January (Box-folder 207: 6)
    - 1980 January (Box-folder 207: 7)
    - 1980 February (Box-folder 207: 8)
    - 1980 July-October (Box-folder 207: 9)
    - 1980 August-October (Box-folder 207: 10)
    - 1980 September (Box-folder 208: 1)
    - 1980 October (Box-folder 208: 2)
    - 1980 December-1981 January (Box-folder 208: 3)
    - 1981 December-1982 February (Box-folder 208: 4)
    - 1987 March (Box-folder 208: 5)
    - 1987 March-April (Box-folder 208: 6)
    - 1987 July-September (Box-folder 208: 7)
    - 1988 April-May (Box-folder 208: 8)
    - 1989 February-March (Box-folder 208: 9-10)
    - 1991 June-July (Box-folder 209: 1)
    - 1992 October-December (Box-folder 209: 2)
    - 1993 November (Box-folder 209: 3)
    - 1997 October-November (Box-folder 209: 4)
    - 1998 February-March (Box-folder 209: 5-6)
    - Turkey and Georgia diary, 1998 May (Box-folder 209: 7)
    - Georgia diary, 1998 May-June (Box-folder 209: 8)
    - Across Asia diary, 1998 June-July (Box-folder 210: 1)
    - 1998 July-August (Box-folder 210: 2)
    - 1998 August-September (Box-folder 210: 3)
    - 1998 October-December (Box-folder 210: 4)
    - 1999 March-April (Box-folder 210: 5)
    - Ethiopia diary, 1999 April (Box-folder 210: 6)
    - 1999 September-October (Box-folder 210: 7)
    - 1999 October-November (Box-folder 210: 8)
    - Ethiopia notebook, 2000 May-June (Box-folder 210: 9-10)
    - 2000 November-December (Box-folder 211: 1)
    - 2000 November (Box-folder 211: 2)
    - 2001 October (Box-folder 211: 3)
    - Ethiopian journeys diary, 2001 October-December (Box-folder 211: 4-5)
    - Ethiopia diary, 2002 November (Box-folder 211: 6)
  - Reports, 2007 (Box-folder 211: 7)
  - Tedo Japaridze, 2004-2009 (Box-folder 211: 8)
  - Correspondence and materials regarding Circassia, 2007-2008 (Box-folder 212: 1)
  - Association for Central Asian Studies, 1986-1995 (Box-folder 212: 2)
  - "Reflections on Georgia" by Paul B Henze, 1998 (Box-folder 212: 3)
  - Central Eurasian Studies Society, 2001-2007 (Box-folder 212: 4)
  - Jamestown Circassian Conference, 2007 May 21 (Box-folder 212: 5)
  - Miscellaneous meetings - Caucasus, Central Asia, Russia, etc., 1998-2002 (Box-folder 212: 6)
  - Jan Nowak Jezioranski, 1969-2005 (Box-folder 212: 7-8)
  - Ato Fasil Ayeau Zeleke, 1992-2006 (Box-folder 212: 9)
  - Ethiopian Embassy, 2009 (Box-folder 212: 10)
  - Ethiopian American Foundation, 1995-2009 (Box-folder 213: 1)
  - Ethiopian Community Development Council, 1995-2007 (Box-folder 213: 2)
  - Project Mercy, 1996-2010 (Box-folder 213: 3)
  - Encyclopedia Aethiopica, 1998-2009 (Box-folder 213: 4)
  - Philip Marsden, 2003-2007 (Box-folder 213: 5)
  - Ken Frantz, 2001-2009 (Box-folder 213: 6)
  - Port Bridge Project, 2001-2006 (Box-folder 213: 7)
  - Michael Gervers, 2007-2009 (Box-folder 213: 8)
  - Gerard Prunier Dictionary of Contemporary Ethiopia, 2003-2006 (Box-folder 213: 9)
  - Tekalign Gedamu, 2006-2008 (Box-folder 214: 1)
  - Shiferaw Bekele, 2001-2009 (Box-folder 214 :2)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies Records, 1993 (Box-folder 214: 3)
  - Central Asia, 1995 January (Box-folder 214: 4)
  - The Delano Eagle Vol. LXX no. 33, 1942 March 5 (Box-folder 214: 5)
  - University of Chicago records, 1946 (Box-folder 214: 6)
  - University of Maine records, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 214: 7)
  - Article in German, 1996 (Box-folder 214: 8)
  - Miscellaneous articles and correspondence, 1969-1990 (Box-folder 214: 9-10)
  - National Foreign Affairs Training Center (NFATC) Seminar on Georgia, 1995 September 5 (Box-folder 215: 1)
  - Materials regarding Georgia, 1999 (Box-folder 215: 2)
  - Book reviews, 1999 (Box-folder 215: 3)
  - London Georgia, 2002 October (Box-folder 215: 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985-2004 (Box-folder 215: 5)
  - Polish Award, 1998 (Box-folder 215: 6)
  - National Endowment for Democracy seminar on "The Unfinished Revolution,", 1991 (Box-folder 215: 7)
  - Chechnya, 2000 (Box-folder 215: 8)
  - Harvard Kennedy School, 1994 (Box-folder 215: 9)
  - Paper regarding history of Monschau (Box-folder 215: 10-11)
  - Military Governmental Operational Reports, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 215: 12)
  - Military Government (MG) Operational Reports, MG Detachment I4G2-H76 Landkreise Monschau (Rheinland) and Beidenkopf (Grosshessen), Germany, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 215: 13)
  - Military Government documents, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 216: 1-2)
  - History of Monschau book Zwischen Zwei Fronten (Kriegstagebuch des LK Monschau), 1952 (Box-folder 216: 3)
  - Book regarding the textile industry in Monschau, Tuchfabriquen in Montjoie (Box-folder 216: 4)
  - Wunder Der Heimat by Ludwig Mathar (Box-folder 216: 5)
  - Sieben Seen Land (Box-folder 216: 6)
  - 125 Jahre Kreis Monschau (Box-folder 216: 7)
  - Maps, 1964-1969 (Map case Map case)
- 2014 December Incremental Materials (Box 217-264)
  - Correspondence, travel documentation, and writings, 1947-2010
    Includes correspondence, travel documentation, research materials, and writings, as well as notes and transcripts from diaries.
    - Marie Broxup, 1987-2002 (Box-folder 217: 1)
    - Michael Radu, 2002 (Box-folder 217: 2)
    - John D. Panitza, 1971-1982 (Box-folder 217: 3)
    - Francisco W. Cleaves, 1950-1960 (Box-folder 217: 4)
    - Gerald Robbins, 1991-2003 (Box-folder 217: 5)
    - David Anthony, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 217: 6)
    - The Carter Administration and the "Arc of Crisis," 1977-1981, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 217: 7)
      From the Cold War International History Project and the National Security Archive.
    - Melvin J. Lasky, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 217: 8)
    - Stuart Munro-Hay, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 217: 9)
    - Wall Street Journal correspondence, 1981-2005 (Box-folder 217: 10)
    - Paul B. Henze biographic notes, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 218: 1)
    - Paul B. Henze press, 2000 (Box-folder 218: 2)
    - Paul B. Henze biographic materials (Box-folder 218: 3-4)
    - Shama Books, 2000-2007 (Box-folder 218: 5)
    - Civilian Conservation Corps, 2009 (Box-folder 218: 6)
    - "Whither Georgia," reflections by Paul Henze, 2004 (Box-folder 218: 7)
    - XIIth International Conference of Ethiopian Studies, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 218: 8)
    - Pope plot, 2005 (Box-folder 218: 9)
      Article, "How the Elite Media and the CIA Failed to Investigate the 1981 Papal Assassination Attempt."
    - "Recollections of Radio Free Europe: Its Evolution in the 1950s and the Hungarian Revolution" by Paul B. Henze, 1996 (Box-folder 218: 10)
    - "The United States and the Horn of Africa: History and Current Prospects" by Paul B. Henze, 1990 (Box-folder 218: 11)
    - Rand reviews, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 218: 12)
    - "Twilight of the USSR" by Paul Henze, 1990 (Box-folder 218: 13)
    - Festschrift for Professor Stanislas Chojnacki, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 218: 14)
    - Radio Free Europe daily log, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 218: 15)
    - We All Talk, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 218: 16)
      A publication of Delano High School, Delano, Minnesota.
    - We All Talk, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 219: 1-2)
    - Travel articles, 1940s (Box-folder 219: 3)
    - Investment opportunities for tourism in Turkey (Box-folder 219: 4)
    - Trip to Italy and Turkey, 1981 (Box-folder 219: 5)
    - Trip to Turkey, 1982 (Box-folder 219: 6)
    - Turkey trip, 1982 (Box-folder 219: 7)
    - Trip to England, Italy, and Turkey, 1983 (Box-folder 219: 8-10)
    - Trip to Turkey, 1984 (Box-folder 219: 11)
    - Trip to Oman, Yemen, Ethiopia (Box-folder 220: 1)
    - Trip to Dominican Republic, 1983 (Box-folder 220: 2)
    - Trip to Turkey, 1984 (Box-folder 220: 3)
    - Trip to England and Turkey (Ditchley/Oxford), 1984 (Box-folder 220: 4)
    - BIA archeological travel notes (Box-folder 220: 5)
    - Trip to Turkey (via Munich), 1989 (Box-folder 220: 6)
    - Trip to Turkey, 1989 August-September (Box-folder 220: 7)
    - Turkish reminiscences for Aktuel, 1994 (Box-folder 220: 8)
    - Turkish traveling materials, 1982 (Box-folder 220: 9)
    - Notes, correspondence, travel documents regarding Turkey, 1985 (Box-folder 220: 10)
    - Trip to Africa and Europe, 1988 (Box-folder 220: 11)
    - Trip to Italy and England, 1988 June (Box-folder 220: 12)
    - Trip to Turkey, 1985 January-February (Box-folder 220: 13)
      Includes shorthand notes.
    - Birgitte and Erling Dessau, 1978 (Box-folder 220: 14)
    - Classical map of Asia Minor, 1957 (Box-folder 221: 1)
    - Trip to Turkey, 1986 March-April (Box-folder 221: 2)
    - Materials regarding Turkey, 1964-1978 (Box-folder 221: 3)
    - Trip to England and Turkey, 1986 October-November (Box-folder 221: 4)
    - Trip to Turkey, 1987 June-July (Box-folder 221: 5)
    - Miscellaneous materials (Box-folder 221: 6)
    - Trip to Belgium, England, Germany and Turkey, 1985 June-July (Box-folder 221: 7)
    - Trip to Turkey, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 221: 8-10)
    - "Socio-Demographic and Educational Changes in Modern Turkey" by John Kolars, 1983 (Box-folder 221: 11)
    - Typed narrative (Box-folder 221: 12)
    - Turkey travels, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 221: 13-14)
      Includes shorthand diary and transcripts.
    - Hasan Dag and region (Box-folder 221: 15)
    - Turkey archeology (Box-folder 221: 16)
    - Life in Ankara, 1974 (Box-folder 221: 17)
    - Trip to Turkey, 1970 (Box-folder 221: 18)
    - Iraq, 2007 (Box-folder 222: 1)
    - Putin test, 1994-2000 (Box-folder 222: 2)
    - Islam, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 222: 3)
    - Agca Pope, 2005-2010 (Box-folder 222: 4)
    - Ethiopian elections, 2010 (Box-folder 222: 5)
    - Essay reaction, 2010 (Box-folder 222: 6)
    - "Ethiopia in Mengistu's Final Years,", 2008 (Box-folder 222: 7)
    - Samuel Gebru (Box-folder 222: 8)
    - Shama, 2008 (Box-folder 222: 9)
    - Lot-Clapham review, 2001 (Box-folder 222: 10)
    - Lot Roger Kaplan review, 2000 (Box-folder 222: 11)
    - Lot reviews and announcements, 2003 (Box-folder 222: 12)
    - Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, 2008-2010 (Box-folder 222: 13)
    - National security intelligence, 2007-2009 (Box-folder 222: 14)
    - Ethiopia, Horn, 2010 (Box-folder 222: 15)
    - Metin Sonmez, 2010 (Box-folder 223: 1)
    - Ethiopia, 2007-2010 (Box-folder 223: 2)
    - Aksum Fissenaz, 2008 (Box-folder 223: 3)
    - Tekeda Alemu, 2006-2010 (Box-folder 223: 4)
    - Steffen Wenig, 2008-2010 (Box-folder 223: 5)
    - Arit donations, 2009 (Box-folder 223: 6)
    - Si Bourgin, 1999-2008 (Box-folder 223: 7)
    - Robert Wiren (Nouvelles d'Addis), 2001-2009 (Box-folder 223: 8)
    - Tafari Wossen, 2004-2010 (Box-folder 223: 9)
    - "The Ethiopian Millennium,", 2006-2008 (Box-folder 223: 10)
    - Ethiopia, 2010 (Box-folder 223: 11)
    - Items for Rew, 2010 (Box-folder 223: 12)
    - Abba Tesfamariam Baraki, 2007 (Box-folder 223: 13)
    - Mehmet Tutuncu, 1999-2003 (Box-folder 223: 14)
    - David and Judy Shinks, 1999-2010 (Box-folder 224: 1)
    - Sisay Asefa, 2006-2010 (Box-folder 224: 2)
    - Francine Stone, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 224: 3)
    - Edmund P. Murray, 1972-2005 (Box-folder 224: 4-6)
    - John Colarusso, 2003-2008 (Box-folder 224: 7)
    - Tedo Japaridze, 2010 (Box-folder 225: 1)
    - Kebede Amare, 2001-2009 (Box-folder 225: 2)
    - Donald Levine, 2009-2010 (Box-folder 225: 3)
    - Patrick Gilkes, 2005-2008 (Box-folder 225: 4)
    - Tony Hickey, 2006-2010 (Box-folder 225: 5)
    - Ewa Balicka-Witakowska, 1996-2007 (Box-folder 225: 6)
    - Fisseha Zewdie, 2003-2010 (Box-folder 225: 7)
    - Wolfgang Hahn, 2000-2010 (Box-folder 225: 8)